<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>charity &#8211; InSROland</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/charity-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>lost lore of the historic core</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 01:03:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-logoINSROLandRain-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>charity &#8211; InSROland</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A successful, failed bank job</title>
		<link>/2011/03/31/stonge/</link>
					<comments>/2011/03/31/stonge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 22:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bank robbery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robbery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The desperate man walked into the Bank of America branch and crossed the lobby to the second teller window&#8211;to Mrs. Joy Holker, 28, the one with the kind eyes. He handed her a brown envelope and a note which read &#8220;This is a holdup. Fill up the envelope. Also have a jar of acid.&#8221; She &#8230; <a href="/2011/03/31/stonge/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">A successful, failed bank job</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p><a title="Bank of America, Broadway &amp; 7th (LAPL) by richardschave, on Flickr" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/5578142596/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm6.static.flickr.com/5306/5578142596_c28b006ae9.jpg" alt="Bank of America, Broadway &amp; 7th (LAPL)" width="391" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>The desperate man walked into the Bank of America branch and crossed the lobby to the second teller window&#8211;to Mrs. Joy Holker, 28, the one with the kind eyes. He handed her a brown envelope and a note which read &#8220;This is a holdup. Fill up the envelope. Also have a jar of acid.&#8221; She obeyed, quickly stacking $540 in $10 bills and passing them across the counter. But as she counted, she gave her robber the once-over. She didn&#8217;t buy it, not from this guy. As he turned away, she came out from behind the counter and chased him onto Broadway, screaming &#8220;Stop that man!&#8221;</p>
<p><a title="victim by richardschave, on Flickr" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/5578092128/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm6.static.flickr.com/5224/5578092128_1e47afc949.jpg" alt="victim" width="149" height="323" /></a></p>
<p class="p2">A motorcycle cop, Charles Randolph, heard her cries, as did patrolman R. Mierdiercks. They took off after the robber, who had darted east on 7<span class="s1"><sup>th</sup></span> Street. He turned south down Spring, and tried to hide in a parking lot mid-block. They busted him there, and he surrendered peacefully.</p>
<p class="p2"><a title="robber by richardschave, on Flickr" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/5578092062/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm6.static.flickr.com/5140/5578092062_bb21599e8b.jpg" alt="robber" width="388" height="500" /></a></p>
<p class="p2">Kenneth St. Onge, 35, had a cap pistol, a bottle of colored water and a sob story. He said he&#8217;d come out from Detroit with his wife and seven sons last September, but couldn&#8217;t find any work. For three weeks, the family slept in their 1947 Studebaker, until wife Esther found work as a waitress. They&#8217;d then moved into a quonset hut at 1480 Landa Street, rent $25 a week plus utilities. After two months, the electric bill came. It was $67, which is how they learned their landlord had wired up an apartment, a trailer and a garage to their meter. With only one pair of decent shoes for all the children, he&#8217;d spend his days driving first one, then another child to attend a class or two, then pick up Esther. Whatever she made in tips, that was their dinner fund. Everything else went to the landlord.</p>
<p class="p2">Then Esther got pregnant again, and couldn&#8217;t stay on her feet all day. They had nothing left.&nbsp; He didn&#8217;t know what else to do, so he did this.&nbsp; &#8220;I guess I knew I&#8217;d get caught, but I figured at least the State would have to take care of my wife and kids,&#8221; he mused.</p>
<p class="p2">Los Angeles briefly fell in love with the sad sack, especially after he appeared on local television bemoaning his fate. Over $1000 in donations poured in, along with clothes for the kids and a job for daddy at City of Hope. The family was offered a furnished home in La Puente for nothing down.</p>
<p class="p2"><a title="family by richardschave, on Flickr" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/5577504841/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm6.static.flickr.com/5132/5577504841_f6b35ccb22.jpg" alt="family" width="500" height="414" /></a></p>
<p class="p2">Just over a month after his life of crime fizzled out, a proud Kenneth St. Onge celebrated Easter with his wife and children in court, as Judge Thurmond Clarke ruled &#8220;Because of your record, your family and your children, I am going to grant you probabtion in this case. For robbing a national bank, I&#8217;ve certainly been very lenient.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p2">&#8220;People have been so kind. I know everything is going to turn out all right now. This is,&#8221; said St. Onge, &#8220;the best break I ever had.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p2">And all he had to do to get it was to cross over to the dark side. There&#8217;s a lesson in there somewhere, we guess, maybe nothing more profound than that most folks like to hear about someone who&#8217;s got it even worse than they do.</p>
<p class="p3">&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Photos: Bank of America from LAPL, others Los Angeles Times</em></p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2011/03/31/stonge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Mystery Skull of Boyd Street</title>
		<link>/2009/08/05/boydstreetskull/</link>
					<comments>/2009/08/05/boydstreetskull/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 02:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[location tag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moustache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skull]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Walking in the alley behind the Sisters of Mercy building, where unfortunates were fed and housed, Fred Forsberg made a grim discovery: a partially mummified section of a human skull, with incongruously handsome, twirled moustaches above the former lips. The top of the skull had been neatly sawn off, suggesting the corpse had paid a &#8230; <a href="/2009/08/05/boydstreetskull/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Mystery Skull of Boyd Street</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>Walking in the alley behind the Sisters of Mercy building, where unfortunates were fed and housed, Fred Forsberg made a grim discovery: a partially mummified section of a human skull, with incongruously handsome, twirled moustaches above the former lips. The top of the skull had been neatly sawn off, suggesting the corpse had paid a visit to an anatomical laboratory. </p>
<p>Forsberg attempted to interest the police in his discovery, but to them it looked too old to be worth investigating. They did, however, deign to attach a note which read &#8220;ex-police reporter&#8221; and parked the relic in the station&#8217;s reporter&#8217;s room. And it was this prank which resulted in a few inches of column space in the <span style="font-style: italic;">Times</span> the following day, and keeps alive the memory of this nameless posthumous denizen of SRO Land. Here&#8217;s to ya, fella, whoever you were.</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009/08/05/boydstreetskull/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
